Help on module QGA_BCQO_sim:

NAME
    QGA_BCQO_sim

DESCRIPTION
    .. module:: QGA_QF.py
        :synopsis: Implements the QGA based on different registers which are pseudo cloned and swapped to implement
        crossover, and semi-sorted to implement selection. This version allows a quantum fitness criteria. Which is
        a fitness criteria defined on a basis which is not known beforehand, although an oracle is needed.
        This GA model is only valid when the fitness can be evaluated by pairs.
        This version implements the cloning subroutine using the Biomimetic Cloning of Quantum Observables (BCQO).
    .. moduleauthor::  Ruben Ibarrondo (rubenibarrondo@gmail.com)

FUNCTIONS
    qga_qf_test(fitness_states, samples, dirpath)
        Not updated to QGA_QF.
        :return:
    
    quantum_genetic_algorithm(fitness_criteria, fitness_basis=None, init_population=None, n=None, cl=None, generation_number=100, pm=0.01, mutation_pattern=None, mutation_unitary='x', projection_method='r', pre_projection_unitary='I', store_path=None, track_fidelity=None, track_only_reg_states=True)
        Quantum Genetic Algorithm.
        WARNING! In this version dense matrices are used to represent the density matrix, quantum_mats.rho are not supported
        yet.
        
        Parameters
        ----------
        fitness_criteria: function
            The criteria evaluated in the auxiliar canonical basis.
                criteria(x,y) = { True, if f(x)<f(y); False, if f(x)>=f(y)}
        fitness_basis: np.array
            The basis in which the fitness_criteria should be evaluated to apply the fitness oracle, each problem basis
            state's coefficients are writen in each column.
            It describes a basis change for the state of a register, from the canonical basis to the problem basis.
            Defaults to None, not basis rotation
        init_population: list, rho, np.array, None
            If list, it is a list of lists describing the classical population,
            must fulfil len(init_population) * len(init_population[0]) = N*cl
            If rho, describes the initial state,
            must fulfil init_population.nq = N*cl.
            If np.array, describes the initial state as a density matrix,
            must fulfil init_population.shape[0] = 2**(N*cl).
            If None, a random state is generated using N and cl.
        n: int
            Number of registers (required). Preferred multiple of four.
        cl: int
            Number of qubits in each register (required). Preferred even.
        generation_number: int
            Number of generation for the genetic algorithm. Defaults to 100.
        pm: float, list
            Probability of bitwise mutation. Defaults to 0.01. Can be overwritten by mutation_pattern.
            If list, it contains the probability of applying each mutation unitary in the mutation_unitary list.
            Probabilities are exclusive, so they must add up to less than one and at most one mutation unitary will be
            applied in each qubit in each generation.
            The length of this array and the mutation_unitary array must match.
        mutation_pattern: list of list of int
            For each generation indicates which qubits to mutate. Defaults to None, using pm=0.01. Overwrites pm.
            Mutation pattern does not support using a set of mutation unitaries for mutation.
        mutation_unitary: np.array, string, list
            If 2x2 np.array matrix describes the mutation unitary.
            If string, one of the following options can be used:
                'not' or 'x' : np.array([[0,1],[1,0]])
                'r': random unitary is generated for each mutation
                'I': identity
                'H': Hadamard gate
            If list, contains a set of mutation unitaries. They will be applied exclusively according to their probability
            determined in the pm array. Both array's lenght must match.
            Defaults to 'x'.
        projection_method: string
            One of the following options can be used:
                'r': the qubits is randomly projected to 0 or 1, according to the amplitude of each state, and only the
                    state according with that value is kept. A pure state would allways yield another pure state after
                    projection.
                'ptrace': the partial trace for that qubits is computed and the density matrix is extended to recover the
                    original dimensions. This may yield a density matrix not in a pure state. It preserves all the
                    statistics related to measurements but it may have a high computational cost.
            Defaults to 'r'.
        pre_projection_unitary:  np.array, string
            If np.array matrix describes the unitary to apply before projection to a register.
            This does not enable changing the acilla measuring basis.
            It can be used to measure in different bases.
            If string, one of the following options can be used:
                'not' or 'x' : np.array([[0,1],[1,0]]) for each qubit in the register
                'r': random unitary is generated for each mutation (not supported yet)
                'I': identity
                'H': Hadamard gate for each qubit in the register
            Defaults to 'I'.
        store_path: string, None
            String describing the path to save the progress.
            If None the progress is not saved.
            Defaults to None.
        track_fidelity: list of states
            List of states for which the fidelity of each registers is tracked.
            Only pure states described with a np.array vector are supported.
            If None the fidelity is not tracked.
            Defaults to None.
        track_only_reg_states: boolean
            True if only the partial density matrix of each register separately should be saved.
            False if the whole density matrix should be saved, this could be too expensive.
            Defaults to True.
        Returns
        -------
        dict:
            Contains the final state, fidelity track...
    
    time(...)
        time() -> floating point number
        
        Return the current time in seconds since the Epoch.
        Fractions of a second may be present if the system clock provides them.

FILE
    c:\users\110773\downloads\qga\qga_bcqo_sim.py


